# Awab Saif

Jiddah, Makkah, Saudi Arabia



Awabtaz9090@gmail.com



0550686506



linkedin.com/in/awab-saif

### **Summary**

Hello, I am Awab, Programmer and Frontend Developer, Experienced UI developer trained in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and React.js.

Bachelor of Computer Applications (BCA) -Chandigarh University. I previously worked in managing the WordPress site and also in IT and data entry, At the university, I learned some programming languages, including C, Java and Python, I have experience in Office, Photoshop and accounting programs

### **Experience**



#### website manager and IT employee

Petra Stars Company

Jan 2022 - Jun 2023 (1 year 6 months)

I am worked as a wholesale website manager and IT employee with Petra Stars Company.

# OXO of accounting software

Ksab Information Technology Company

Sep 2021 - Mar 2022 (7 months)

I worked as a sale and marketing of accounting software on commission and technical support for clients of the Kasab Information Technology Company

# Delivery

Mrsool app

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021 (5 months)

I worked as a delivery conductor with Mrsool app

# ■ Distributor and merchandise delivery official

Diamond Tawafuq Company

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020 (4 months)

I worked in an auto parts Diamond Tawafuq Company for 3 months

# Tickets employee

almosafer bus travel agency

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020 (8 months)

I worked for almosafer bus travel agency

# Delivery

Mrsool app

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019 (4 months)

I worked as a delivery conductor with Mrsool app 4 month.

# marketing of accounting software

#### Self-employed

Jun 2018 - Aug 2019 (1 year 3 months)

I worked sale and marketing of accounting software on commission and technical support for clients of for my father's accounting program

# Secretary

njd al majd company Jun 2018 - Sep 2018 (4 months)

#### **Education**

# **CHANDIGARH UNIVERSITY**

Bachelor's degree, Computer Application - BCA

2021 - 2024

I am currently a student at Chandigarh University and I am studying in the online Bachelor of Computer Applications (BCA) program. This program takes three years, from 2021 to 2024, and consists of 6 semesters, each semester of 6 months. The program includes skills such as programming languages, Python, technical support, C programming, and Java.

### **Scrimba**

Course, React.js

Jun 2023 - Jun 2023

The ultimate React 101 - the perfect starting point for any React beginner. Learn the basics of modern React by solving 140+ interactive coding challenges and building eight fun projects.

# **Scrimba**

Course, JavaScript

May 2023 - May 2023

basics of JavaScript by solving 140+ interactive coding challenges. Along the way will build a game, a browser extension, and even a mobile app.

# **Scrimba**

Course, HTML and CSS

Apr 2023 - Apr 2023

HTML and CSS through building and deploying five awesome projects. It is also fully interactive, with over 75 coding challenges.

# Zamerica-n English app

English, English Language and Literature/Letters
Jun 2018 - Feb 2021

Pass the first level test

#### Proleaders Institute

English, English Language

Dec 2020 - Jan 2021

Total training hours: 30 Grade: Excellent.

### Khalid Bin Al Waleed Jeddah

High School, High School natural sciences

May 2015 - May 2018

The Khalid Bin Al Waleed High School in Jeddah is a High School in natural sciences. I joined in May 2015 and graduated in May 2018. I got a GPA of 86.33 and a very good grade. My period of study at the school was full of challenges and achievements and the school helped me to develop my skills and knowledge in the field of natural sciences.

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

Analysing Patterns in Data and Storytelling - upGrad

c34dbf2c-32ea-442c-a6ee-1bd8154a8d28

# JavaScript Basics from Scratch - upGrad

Issued Jan 2023 - Expires Feb 2023 8cb8e5c5-e93f-4771-b14f-20479fc2a74f

# The Frontend Developer Career Path - Scrimba

Issued Jun 2023 - Expires Jul 2023

# Advanced React - Scrimba

Issued Jul 2023 - Expires Jul 2023

#### **Skills**

Routing • GitHub • Figma (Software) • Code Review • Responsive Web Design • API • REST APIs • React.js • frontend developer • JavaScript